Eric Mbouwe

Ruby Developer

ericmbouwe@yahoo.fr

+(237)696278898

GitHub • LinkedIn • Portfolio

Experienced Ruby developer with 3 years of experience in web application design and development. Strong skills in HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript/TypeScript, and Front frameworks (Angular, React). Experience designing REST APIs and being comfortable with Ruby on Rails for writing backends. Working knowledge of Agile methods(SCRUM, Kanban, TDD) and Jira, Confluence and Trello tools. Competent with CSS pre-processors, mixins, style sheets with variables, flexboxes, and responsive design. Experience in carrying out personal projects.

Languages: French (native), English (level C1)

EXPERIENCES

November 2022 - present

Ruby Developer

Qhare, France (Remote work)

- Added search and filter features to CRM to simplify lead search. the CRM has greatly improved its lead search capabilities, providing a seamless experience for users.
- Setting up a lead tracking system to allow users to track leads and convert them into customers
- Secure the CRM by implementing best practices for user authentication, authorization, data protection, and firewall setup.
- Collaborating with the Agile development team to deliver new and exciting features to customers across France, while ensuring timely delivery before competitors.
- provide guidance and support to developers who may be new to the field. My goal is to help them improve their skills and expand their understanding of the technology stack.
- Engage in pair programming and test-driven development with fellow developers to deliver exceptional code of the highest quality.
- Team up with the group and propose enhancements for the product and development.

September 2021 - present

Technical support developer

Microverse, United States (Remote work)

- After conducting thorough reviews, I have evaluated more than 500 projects that encompass JavaScript, React.js, Ruby, and Rails.
- Assist in enhancing KPI accomplishment by 40% by mentoring and assessing the performance of two recently recruited developers.

March 2020 - October 2022

Frontend Developer

Zerofiltre, France (Remote work)

- Design, development and implementation of a high-quality user interface for the article creation and course delivery application, including server-side rendering (SSR) using Angular
- Efficiently manage application state and share data between components with RxJS and Redux.
- Creating a robust and expandable application architecture for easy maintenance and future development.
- Implement a system of continuous integration and continuous deployment using Jenkins and Docker-Kubernetes.
- Include internationalization features, ensuring that users from all over the globe can enjoy a more user-friendly experience.
- Simplified the process of discovering content by creating and incorporating search and filtering features.

- Implemented a content management system that enables authors to effortlessly produce articles and courses.
- I successfully integrated the application's backend by utilizing REST APIs.
- Established a secure environment for the application by adhering to the best security practices.
- Use automated testing tools (such as Sonarqube) to guarantee the quality of our code and to reduce the occurrence of any bugs.

January 2019 - February 2020

Frontend Developer

GS1 Cameroon, Douala

- Development of the barcode interaction and ordering web platform
- Implement a clear and effective navigation system to help users navigate the e-commerce site (kobo.promo).
- Efficiently manage application state and share data between components with RxJS and Redux.
- Facilitate product search on e-commerce sites with search and filtering features.
- I implemented a shopping cart functionality that enables users to browse and buy products through the web.
- Creating highly responsive UI Components

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

February 2020 - June 2021

Full stack development program (Certification equivalent)

Microverse, United States (Remote)

- Over 1500 hours mastering algorithms, data structures, design patterns and full-stack development while developing projects in Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux and NodeJs
- Collaborate with international remote developers using GitFlow standard on GitHub through daily standups and remote pair programming to develop skills.

October 2018 - June 2020

Master MIAGE (Incomplete) (Master's equivalent)

University of Douala, Cameroon

- Skills in project management and system design.
- The topic at hand pertains to business intelligence and data warehousing, as it has been explored in previous research.

January 2018 - October 2018

Java Development Program (Certification equivalent)

Objis - 10000 Codeurs, Cameroon

• Learned Java and object-oriented programming for 300+ hours. Gained hands-on experience with JEE, Swing, Spring Framework, JavaScript, and React through project work.

October 2014 - June 2017

Bachelor's degree in management sciences (Baccalaureate equivalent) University of Douala, Cameroon

• I took a variety of courses including micro and macroeconomics, finance, statistics, probability, financial mathematics, and linear algebra.

REFERENCES

References on request